Reeve Family Papers, 1767-1866 Ms 18
Archivists' Toolkit
Reeve Family Papers, 1767-1866
Ms 18
Archivists' Toolkit
0.5 Linear feet (1 box, 375 items)
This collection includes correspondence and other papers of the Tapping Reeve family of Litchfield, CT and also includes items from Aaron Burr and Lyman Beecher.
Reeve family
Conditions Governing Access note
There are no restrictions on access to this collection.
Scope and Contents note
This list is made up primarily of personal letters coming in to Tapping Reeve and his immediate family, and to and from Aaron Burr. There are also bills, receipts, notes and one deed belonging to Tapping Reeve, a few outgoing letters and some miscellaneous items.
The letters are arranged alphabetically by correspondent under the Reeve family members listed in the biographical note and Aaron Burr. Much of the collection has been transcribed. The final two folders hold copies of Amelia Ogden's will and probate records and the sermon preached at the funeral of Tapping Reeve by Lyman Beecher. Some of the letters, bills and checks have been laminated.
Biographical/Historical note
Tapping Reeve (1744-1823), the son of Presbyterian minister Abner Reeve, was born in Brookhaven, NY and educated at the College of New Jersey (Princeton). He moved to Connecticut in 1771, was admitted to the bar in 1772, and moved to Litchfield in 1773. Tapping Reeve is noted as the founder and first teacher of the Litchfield School of Law, as judge of the Connecticut Superior Court, and as Chief Justice of the Supreme Court of Errors. He was active in the political, civic and religious affairs of his community, publishing many legal and political works throughout his lifetime. He was noted as an advocate of equal education and equal legal rights for women.
Sarah (Sally) Burr Reeve (1754-1797), first wife of Tapping Reeve, was the daughter of President Burr of Princeton and sister of Aaron Burr (1756-1836). She was in poor health throughout much of her adult life.
Elizabeth (Betsy) Thompson Reeve (1774-1842) was Tapping's second wife and was born in Watertown, CT. They married in Bethlehem in 1798. She may have been his housekeeper at one time.
Aaron Burr Reeve (1780-1809), only child of Tapping Reeve, married Annabelle Shelton (1798-1849). Their son Tapping Burr Reeve (1809-1829) died while a student at Yale College.
Amelia Ogden (1779-1866) was described by Lyman Beecher's daughter as "another inmate of the family...an orphan who held the place of a daughter in the household."
Bibliography
A Genealogical Register of the Inhabitants of the Town of Litchfield, Connecticut by George C. Woodruff, Hartford Press, 1980.
Autobiography, Correspondence, etc. of Lyman Beecher, D. D., ed. by Charles Beecher, New York, Harper and Sons, 1865.
Dictionary of American Biography, Charles Scribner's, New York, 1935.
The Bench and Bar of Litchfield County, Connecticut, 1709-1909, by Dwight C. Kilbourn, Litchfield, 1909.
Custodial History note
The origin of these items is unclear, possibly a donation by Annie Burr Jennings.
Beecher, Lyman, 1775-1863; Burr, Aaron, 1756-1836; Ogden, Amelia, 1779-1866; Reeve, Aaron Burr, 1780-1809; Reeve, Elizabeth Thompson, 1774-1842; Reeve, Sarah Burr, 1754-`797; Reeve, Tapping Burr, 1809-1829; Reeve, Tapping, 1744-1823; Correspondence.; Judges--Connecticut--Litchfield--Correspondence.; Lawyers--Connecticut--Litchfield--Correspondence.; Real property--Connecticut--Litchfield County.; Receipts (financial records)
- Aaron Burr, 1775-1831; Folder A; 11 items
  - Timothy Edwards, 1775
  - Sally Reeve, 1777, 1779, 1780, n.d.; 4 items
  - Tapping Reeve, 1786, n.d.; 3 items
  - Calvin Goddard, 1831
  - Receipt, 1790
- Aaron Burr, Folder B; 4 items
  - Photocopies of correspondence, outgoing to P. Van Gaasbeck, 1795
- Transcripts of Items in Folders A and B, Folder C; 17 items
- Tapping Reeve Outgoing Correspondence, Folder D; 6 items
  - Sally Reeve, 1773, n.d.; 2 items
  - Betsy Reeve, n.d.; 3 items
  - Unidentified, n.d.
- Tapping Reeve Incoming Correspondence, 1772-1823; Folder E; 20 items
  - W. Barnes, 1820
  - Annabelle Sheldon Reeve Burr, 1814
  - Thaddeus Burr, 1775, 1783
  - Peter Colt, 1772
  - John P. Cushman, 1820
  - Pierpont Edward, 1782
  - Sam W. Hopkins, 1812
  - Jos. Johnson, 1820
  - Alfred Lathrop, 1823
  - Ezekiel Lewis, 1781
  - Charles Marsh, 1820
  - V. Maxcy, 1809
  - John Moseley, 1820
  - Eldred Simkins, 1820
  - J. C. Smith, 1820
  - Melancton Smith, 1792
  - Benjamin Tallmadge, 1807; 2 items
  - John Woodhull (bestowing of Princeton honorary degree on Tapping), 1813
- Tapping Reeve Legal and Financial Notes, 1789-1807; Folder F; 7 items
  - Thomas Collier, n.d.
  - Caleb Baron, 1802
  - Daniel Potter, 1807
  - David Pierpont, 1789
  - Mr. Stoddard, n.d.
  - Col. Talmadge, n.d.
  - Agreement re: use of sawmill between Asa Sanford and Tapping Reeve, 1805
- Tapping Reeve Financial Records, 1791-1820; Folder G; 28 items
  - Receipts from:
    - Joseph Belden, 1820
    - Thomas Brau and Austin Ginby, 1815
    - Dan Hopkins, 1806
    - Hezekiah Howe, 1816
    - H. Howe and P. I. I. Barnard, 1816
    - Dan Huntington, 1805
    - Joel Jones, 1819
    - Charles G. Reichel, 1795
    - Roger Skinner, 1790, 1798
  - Promissory notes and receipts
    - Phoenix Branch Bank, Litchfield, 1818, 1819
    - Tax receipts, 1790, 1816
    - Connecticut Bible Society, 1811, 1815, 1816
    - American Board Commissioners for Foreign Missions, 1819
    - Samuel W. Hopkins, 1809
    - Robert Lenox, 1823
    - B. Tallmadge & Co., 1791, 1793
    - Robert Whitten
  - Notes, bills, bills of credit
    - Betsey Collins, 1815
    - I. Cooke, 1808, 1812
    - Ezra Bronson, 1792
    - Jon Bunell and John Ensign, 1793
    - Dorcas Post, 1807
    - William Mitchel, 1781
    - Jesse Moss vs. Antony Taylor, n.d.
    - Moses Seymour, 1805
  - Quit claim deed, Selectman of Litchfield to T. Reeve, 1813
- Transcripts of Some Items in Folders D-G, Folder H; 56 items
- Sarah Burr Reeve Incoming Correspondence, 1767-1774; Folder I; 17 items
  - Eunice Burr, 1773
  - Sally DeVoe, 1790, 1774
  - Pamela Dwight, 1771
  - Polly Grant, 1767, 1771, 1773, 1774
  - Polly Lyman, n.d.
  - Mary Ogden, 1772
  - Theodosia Provost, 1770
  - R. E., n.d.
  - S. O., n.d.
- Elizabeth Reeve Incoming Correspondence, 1809-1829; Folder J; 17 items
  - C. E. Beecher, 1809
  - Lyman and Harriet Beecher, 1809
  - A. G. Bris and Sarah Bush, 1829
  - Geo. Brach, 1824
  - M. R. Cornelius (Dr. Kissam's notes), n.d.
  - Harriet Corning, n.d.
  - Sally Corning, n.d.
  - Harriet Cowles, 1829
  - Ogden Edwards, 1807
  - Jos. C. Hornblower, 1829
  - Helen Kent, 1829
  - Mr. Kilbourn, n.d.
  - John Cotton Smith, 1829
  - S. H. Tomlinson, 1820, n.d.
  - Unidentified, n.d.
- Transcripts of Items in Folders I and J, Folder K; 36 items
- Aaron Burr Reeve Outgoing Correspondence, 1798-1807; Folder L; 17 items
  - Outgoing
    - Mrs. Betsy Reeve, 1798, 1799, 1800, 1801, n.d.
    - Tapping and Betsy Reeve, 1802, n.d.
    - David Bacon, 1809
  - Incoming
    - D. Randolph, 1807
    - H. B. Rogers, n.d.
    - Oliv. Wolcott, 1806
    - Essay: "On a Taste for Science" with note Aaron kept for T. B. Reeve
    - Receipt: J. H. & W. Townsend, 1803
- Thaddeus Burr Reeve Incoming Correspondence, Folder M; 2 items
  - Annabelle and David Burr, 1826
  - Copy of letter from Jeremiah Day, President of Yale College re: TBR's death, 1829
- Transcripts of Some Items in Folders L-M, Folder N; 16 items
- Amelia Ogden Correspondence, 1827-1846; Folder O; 19 items
  - Certificate from Connecticut Historical Society re: donation of cane, 1844
  - Betsy Reeve, n.d.
  - Mr. Burgouyn, 1843
  - V. D. Bonesteel, 1831
  - M. Burgouyn, 1846
  - E. P. Corning, 1833
  - Edward H. Cumming, 1828, 1829, 1830, 1831
  - Mary Ann Delafield, 1827
  - W. Devereux, 1829
- Amelia Ogden Incoming Correspondence, 1829-1841; Folder P; 17 items
  - Henry B. Edwards, 1832
  - George Bourne Farnsworth, n.d.
  - Ward E. Hunt, 1831
  - Theodore Woolsey Porter, 1831
  - Benj. Price, 1829, 1820, 1832, 1833
  - C. W. Rogers, 1833
  - Julia Sherrill (includes poem), 1829
  - Ann Elice, 1832
  - E. J. J., 1833
  - Harriette, 1836
  - unidentified, 1829
  - N. S., n.d.
  - unidentified, 1849
- Transcripts of Some Items in Folders O-P, Folder Q; 34 items
- Miscellaneous Items, Folder R; 8 items
  - Printing estimate, n.d.
  - Bill, Miss Brace, 1812
  - Bill, Alexander Catlin to Pierpont Edward, 1776
  - Letter to Mrs. Reeve from PWG, n.d.
  - Fragment of letter, 1824
  - John C. Smith vs. Ebenezer Plumb and James Johnson, 1788
  - James Johnston vs. Reuben Smith, 1792
- Miscellaneous Items, Folder S; 30 items
  - Transcripts of some items in Folder R
  - Copy of will and probate records of Amelia Ogden
  - Sermon, Preached at the Funeral of the Hon. Tapping Reeve by Lyman Beecher, D.D., printed by S. S. Smith (photostat of original from Sterling Library, Yale University), 1827